### CYNTHIA I. DICKSON

With a BSc. in Computer Science and having worked as a Frontend Developer for 4 years in various sectors, I love to build formidable products that are top-notch in their user experience and application functionalities.

Lagos, Nigeria +234-806-368-5147 cynthiaiboro@gmail.com github.com/cynthiaiboro

#### **EXPERIENCE**

BUCKHILL SOFTWARE, Zagreb, Croatia — Frontend Developer APRIL 2022 – PRESENT

Write working code from general specifications using best coding practices.

Automated testing methods using Jest and cypress.

Manage code deployment

Document all code according to common development best practices and create technical documentation of project work to facilitate knowledge sharing.

Peer code reviews

Analyse, diagnose and debug faults, errors and bugs (e.g. client incidents).

## THE BULB AFRICA, Lagos, Nigeria — Frontend Developer SEPTEMBER 2020 – FEBRUARY 2022

Translate designs to code and consumed restful APIs
Optimized components for maximum performance across
web-capable devices and browsers

Maintain software workflow, versioning, and testing during development and address any bugs.

# **ENOV8 SOLUTIONS,** Lagos, Nigeria — Frontend Developer FEBRUARY 2020 – AUGUST 2020

Translated designs and wireframes into high-quality code
Built reusable components using Vue concepts and consumed
APIs.

#### **SKILLS**

UI designs to code
Responsive Design
API integration
State Management
Payment gateway
integration
Postman, Swagger to test
endpoints
Git versioning
Docker
Authentication
Authorization
Cloudinary, AWS S3.

#### **TOOLS**

HTML, CSS, SCSS,
Tailwind, Vuetify, SASS,
JavaScript, JQuery, VueJS,
NUXT JS, React JS,
Vuepress, VueX, JEST,
Cypress, GraphQL,
Storybook

**Design tools** - Figma, Adobe XD

#### JIGGLE NIGERIA, Uyo, Nigeria — Frontend Developer

MARCH 2019 - JANUARY 2020

Built product to match the design and specified requirements. Ensured compatibility across multiple devices and operating systems.

Maintained, debugged and fixed issues that arise in your product.

#### **MY PORTFOLIO**

Here is a link to a few projects I've worked on

https://cynthia-dickson.netlify.app/

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Port Harcourt, Port Harcourt - B.Sc January 2014 - June 2018

**Computer Science** 

**Aladumo International High School**, Port Harcourt - Waec

September 2006 - June 2012

#### **OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS**

ExpressWebJS — View

A Node FrameWork with expressive and organised syntax.

I handled versioned documentation with VuePress.

#### **REFERENCES**

Available on request

### PROJECT TRACKING TOOLS

**Code Versioning** GitHub, Gitlab, Bitbucket

**Project Management**Jira, Trello, Airtable,
Asana, Shortcut, Linear

Communication Slack, Microsoft Teams, Google Meet, Zoom, Mattermost

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

Communication,
Teamwork, Leadership,
Attention to details,
organization and
planning.